# **Othman Shareef**

Nationality: Iraqi

**\** (+964) 7507313459

**(**+90) 5369930799

**Gender:** Male

**■ Email address:** othmanosx@gmail.com

**Website:** othman.itechnopro.com

**(Sample of State of** 

in LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/othmanosx

Address: Erbil - Chwar Chra - Hasarook 7 3229 - NO.93, 44001 Erbil (Iraq)

Address: Yakacık MAH. Recep Demir SK. NO:8/17, 06460 Ankara (Turkey)

### **ABOUT ME**

Experienced Website Manager with a demonstrated history of working in the computer industry. Skilled in Software Engineering, Front-end web development, UI Design, Graphic Design, Photography, Translation, Blogging, article writing, software reviewing, and Management. Strong media and communication professional with an engineering degree focused in mechanical engineering from University of Mosul.

# **PROJECTS**

# Weather web app (React JS)

[ 06/02/2021 - 13/02/2021 ]

- Provide detailed weather forecasts over a 6 day period updated each day for more than 2000 cities in the world.
- Charts provide wind speed, temperature, humidity and visibility.

Used libraries and dependencies:

- ∘ react v17.0.1
- o chart.js v2.9.4
- o chartjs-plugin-colorschemes v0.4.0
- fontawesome v5.0.7
- bootstrap v4.0.0
- ∘ jquery v3.2.1
- ajax v1.12.9

Live Demo: https://weather-app-othman.netlify.app

Code Repo: https://github.com/Othmanosx/weather\_app\_is

# **Mood Analyzer (Angular)**

[ 28/01/2021 - Current ]

A web app that analyzes human faces and detects changes with emotions depending on the facial expression of image.

## Technologies

- 1. Angular
- 2. Flask
- 3. Firebase (for deployment)

Code Repo: https://github.com/Othmanosx/MoodApp

# Hangman Game (ReactJS)

[28/01/2021 - 05/02/2021]

Hangman is a word guessing game which I developed using ReactJS Javascript framework in which the user guesses the word generated randomly by the game from an API.

Live Demo: <a href="https://hangman-sand-team.netlify.app/">https://hangman-sand-team.netlify.app/</a>

Code Repo: <a href="https://github.com/Othmanosx/hangman\_react\_js">https://github.com/Othmanosx/hangman\_react\_js</a>

## FindYours (in development)

[ 02/2021 - Current ]

The idea of the project is to help people find their missing stuff, will let people post the things they lost and let people post the things they found, every post will contain the info a user may need to contact the person. Every province will have its own section.

- 1. Technologies and dependencies
- 2. React is
- 3. Material UI CSS Framework
- 4. Firebase
- 5. Redux
- 6. Jest testing
- 7. Prettier
- 8. Eslint

Repo: <a href="https://github.com/murtaja1/find\_yours">https://github.com/murtaja1/find\_yours</a>

# **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

# **Bachelor in Mechanical Engineering**

**Mosul University** 

Address: Mosul (Iraq)

# Front-End Web Development (ReactJS)

**Re:Coded** [ 13/01/2021 - Current ]

Address: Erbil (Iraq)

https://www.re-coded.com/

# **Full Stack Web Development (Python&Angular)**

Kodluyoruz

Address: Ankara (Turkey) https://www.kodluyoruz.org/

# COVID-19: Operational Planning Guidelines and COVID-19 Partners Platform to support country preparedness and response

World Health Organization

https://www.who.int/

# **Management and Facilitation of an After Action Review (AAR)**

World Health Organization

https://www.who.int/

## **Business IT**

Work Well

Address: Minnesota (United States)

https://work-well.org/

# Power Skills: Business Communication, Agile Methodologies, Team Work, Time Management

**Re:Coded** [ 01/2021 - 04/2021 ]

www.re-coded.com

## **Retail sales skills**

mselect

https://www.mselect.ig/

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Web developer

iTECH Website [ 12/2014 - Current ]

- www.itechnopro.com

City: Erbil
Country: Iraq

Email address: info@itechnopro.com

- Website owner, manager and organizer.
- Front-end web developer.
- Professional blogger, copywriter, articles and report writer with 6+ years of experience.
- Graphics designer with 5+ years of experience.
- Marketing & Social Media Specialist.
- Website management and content publishing with excellent skills
- Search Engine Optimization Specialist.
- Offer technical support to company clients and troubleshoot computer problems.

#### **Freelancer**

**Tenoreshare inc.** [ 2016 – Current ]

- https://www.tenorshare.com/

City: Hong Kong Country: China

- English Arabic translator.
- Graphic Designer.
- Data management using Excel.
- Write articles and review and test new products and software.

# **Mechanical engineer**

Municipality of Erbil Governorate [ 07/2018 - 08/2018 ]

City: Erbil
Country: Iraq

- Work on assessing and monitoring project requirements
- Measuring performance of mechanical devices and engines
- Maintaining equipment to ensure it's safe, reliable and efficient
- Using computer-aided design and modeling software
- Producing and implementing designs and check procedures
- Testing, evaluating, modifying and re-testing products
- Writing reports and documentation
- Providing technical advice

### **DIGITAL SKILLS**

## Web Development

Material Ui / Netlify / Redux / CSS Frameworks / CI / CD / DevOps/CICD: Travis CI, Heroku, Netlify, Firebase, Webpack, Jenkins, Terraform / Git workflow / State Management / Sprint Planning / Context API / Scrum / Ag ile Methodology / GIT (GitHub) / VScode / Reactis / Reactls / Web Development: HTML 5, CSS, JavaScript

### Design

AutoCAD / SolidWorks / UI Design (Figma) / Adobe Illustratior / Photoshop

### Other

Microsoft Powerpoint / Organizational and planning skills / Microsoft Office / Microsoft Word / Social Media / Microsoft Excel

## **LANGUAGE SKILLS**

Mother tongue(s):

#### **Arabic**

Other language(s):

# English

LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING C1

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C1 SPOKEN INTERACTION C1

# **Turkish**

LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING C1

**SPOKEN PRODUCTION B2 SPOKEN INTERACTION B2**